chemicool.com 2017-07-09

# About Chemicool

### About Chemicool

Chemicool was the brainchild of David D. Hsu. of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA. The website went online in 1996 and since then we have been trying to help out anyone involved in chemistry. 

The data for this site were acquired with help from the following people; a big thanks goes out to all of them: Cabrol D.; Moore J. W and Kotz J. C. Additionally, the Perkin-Elmer Periodic Table v2.02g was used for Atomic mass, density, volume, group, heat of fusion, heat of vaporization, specific heat, and shells. 

More recently, we have been updating pages with images, YouTube chemistry clips and a lot more information. 

Since the site's launch we have won some awards. "Ten Cool Sites" for Exploratorium Learning Studio's best in Science, Art, & K-12 sites would be our best achievement so far. 

We are working hard to get more of these awards, so keep following our progress. 

I hope you find Chemicool interesting and helpful. 

_Doug Stewart, Ph.D. (Physical Chemistry)_

### To Cite Chemicool

We've had many enquiries about the correct way to cite information from Chemicool, so here's how to do it. 

1\. For online linking to the homepage, please copy and paste one of the following: 

    <a href="http://www.chemicool.com/">Chemicool Periodic Table</a>

or 

    <a href="http://www.chemicool.com/">Periodic Table by Chemicool</a>

To cite this website in an academic document, or any written science report, please use the following MLA compliant citation: 

    Chemicool Periodic Table. 1/30/2020 <http://www.chemicool.com/>.

2\. For online linking to one of the individual pages, please use the following (for carbon) as an example: 

    <a href="http://www.chemicool.com/elements/carbon.html">Carbon</a>

or 

    <a href="http://www.chemicool.com/elements/carbon.html">Carbon Element Facts</a>

To cite this website in an academic document, or any written science report, please use the following MLA compliant citation - again we've used the carbon page as an example. Replace carbon with the page you wish to cite: 

    "Carbon." Chemicool Periodic Table. 1/30/2020 <http://www.chemicool.com/elements/carbon.html>.

### Privacy

Chemicool is an information site and has no aim in collecting personal information about people who visit. If you wish to leave comments on any of the site's pages, you will need to provide an email address. We do not share email addresses with third parties or use them for spamming/advertising/marketing. Non-personal information is gathered from each computer that "hits" the site. This information is used to measure traffic to the site, find broken pages and links, etc. This means that cookies are used. These cookies maintain a record of browsing habits across this site and basic information obtained from browsers. No personal information is contained within these cookies. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any other personal information about you. Cookies and web beacons may be used by companies such as Google serving ads on the site. Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to you based on your visits to sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website. You are welcome to leave any [comments](http://www.chemicool.com/elements/contact-chemicool.html) about the site, and help us improve. 

### Disclaimer and Copyright

The site aims to provide information free at the point of use, but can make no 100% guarantee about the accuracy of the information available on this site. Human error will play a factor in the creation of any web site, and therefore inaccuracies do sometimes arise.

Considerable efforts are made to ensure there are as few errors as possible in the information on this site. In regards to copyright, most information on this website is copyrighted by the webmaster of Chemicool. The webmaster reserves their rights and therefore any breach of copyright in information in regards to this site is against the law and breaches intellectual property rights. 

### Alphabetical Elements List
